KITSUDAR SOMCHANA SENIOR UX/UI DESIGNER

****720-232-7579 kitsudar@gmail.com in @kitsudar https://kitsudar.github.io

Alcohol Monitoring Systems, Littleton, CO

SUMMARY

A designer with a strong blend of creativity, problem solving and UI development to create intuitive and beautiful digital experiences. A motivated self-starter who enjoys transforming ideas into delightful, captivating designs that deliver results in a fast-paced environment.

SKILLS

Design Thinking Process, Qualitative/Quantitative Usability Studies, User Research, Accessibility Standards, HTML5, CSS3, ¡Query/JavaScript, Bootstrap, Sketch, Adobe Xd, Photoshop CC, Illustrator CC, Indesign CC, After Effects CC, Wordpress, Git/Github, Logo/Branding/Styleguide

EXPERIENCE

2015 - Present

Senior UX/UI Designer (2018 - Present)

Responsible for the creation of engaging user experiences for the company's full suite of desktop and mobile applications.

- Successfully managed a feasibility study that validated a new business opportunity that will provide new sales revenue for the company.
- Facilitate UX workshops with cross-functional teams to build empathy and validate users' needs in order to use those insights to ideate on solutions.
- Provide guidance and feedback around UX best practices across the organization.
- Develop a branded component library that led to a complete Design System to provide consistency across the products.

UX/UI Designer (2015 - 2018)

- Worked closely with Product Managers to define the business requirements by understanding customers' needs, motivations and behaviors and translate those insights into viable solutions.
- Conducted qualitative usability testing with customers to validate and iterate on designs.
- Created design artifacts such as storyboard, UX mapping, wireframe, user flow diagram, low to hi fidelity prototypes as part of the Design Thinking Process.
- Participanted in the daily Agile team stand-up to review development and test demos to provide UX feedback and design decisions as needed.
- Hand coded HTML, CSS and Jquery prototypes using Bootstrap framework to support sales demos and lead generation.
- Designed a hybrid mobile application using Ionic framework for users to able to manage their workload on-the-go.

RTD, Denver, CO 2013 - 2015 Graphic/Web Designer

Responsible for the creative vision of the corporate brand and translate them into a best in-class customer experiences for RTD riders. Delivered award-winning creative campaigns and collaborated on extensive system map projects.

Hogan Lovells, Denver, CO 2011 - 2012 Contract designer

Responsible for the complete design of collateral materials, custom proposals, ads, info sheets, custom invitations, signage, firm publications, and digital marketing campaigns.

MoneyGram, Lakewood, CO 2009 - 2011 Contract Designer

Supported the marketing department designing direct mail, advertisements, brochures, presentations, signage, promotional materials and collaterals as needed. Acted as a liaison between the Denver and Dallas offices through a successful relocation project.

EDUCATION/CERTIFICATION

UX Certification

Nielson Norman Group, February 2020

University of Denver

Graduate Certificate, Advanced Study in Web Design and Development, 2014 - 2015

California State University-Long Beach

Bachelor of Fine Arts (BFA), Graphic Design, 2000 - 2004

References available upon request.